The only thing more dangerous than the line being
crossed, is the cop who will cross it.
Training Day is a action, crime, drama film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
On his first day on the job as a narcotics officer, a rookie cop
works with a rogue detective who isn't what he appears.
Alonzo, played by Denzel Washington.
Jake, played by Ethan Hawke.
Roger, played by Scott Glenn.
Stan Gursky, played by Tom Berenger.
Doug Rosselli, played by Harris Yulin.
Lou Jacobs, played by Raymond J. Barry.
Training Day is a 2001 American crime thriller film directed
by Antoine Fuqua and written by David Ayer.
It stars Denzel Washington as Alonzo Harris and Ethan Hawke as Jake Hoyt, two LAPD narcotics officers followed over a
24-hour period in the gang-ridden neighborhoods of Westlake, Echo Park, and South Central Los Angeles.
It also features Scott Glenn, Eva Mendes, Cliff Curtis, Dr.
Dre, Snoop Dogg, and Macy Gray in supporting roles.
Training Day premiered at the Venice Film Festival on September 2, 2001
and was released on October 5, 2001, by Warner Bros.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised Washington
and Hawke's performances but were divided on the screenplay.
The film grossed $104.9 million against a $45 million budget.
The film received numerous accolades and nominations, with Washington's performance earning him the Academy Award
for Best Actor and Hawke being nominated for Best Supporting Actor at the 74th Academy Awards.
A television series based on the film, produced by Jerry Bruckheimer, was
announced in August 2015 and premiered on February 2, 2017, on CBS.
Only Noel Gugliemi, Tom Berenger and Raymond J.
Barry reprised their roles.
The show was cancelled after one season.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, california, police
brutality, poker, bratva (russian mafia).
The tone is dark and emotional.